<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.triliumnext.notes</id>
  <name>Trilium Notes</name>
  <summary>Build your personal knowledge base</summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>AGPL-3.0-only</project_license>
  <developer id="com.triliumnext">
    <name>TriliumNext</name>
  </developer>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/TriliumNext/Trilium</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/TriliumNext/Trilium/issues</url>
  <url type="help">https://github.com/TriliumNext/Trilium/wiki</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/TriliumNext/Trilium</url>
  <description>
    <p>This is a community package of Trilium Notes, maintained independently and unaffiliated with the TriliumNext project. It repackages the official upstream Linux build unmodified.</p>
    <p>Trilium Notes is a free and open-source, cross-platform hierarchical note-taking application with a focus on building large personal knowledge bases. The desktop app is local-first: it keeps its own database and works fully offline, with optional synchronisation to a self-hosted or cloud Trilium server.</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Organise notes into an arbitrarily deep tree; a single note can be placed in multiple places at once (cloning).</li>
      <li>Rich WYSIWYG editing with tables, images, admonitions, math and Markdown import/export, plus dedicated note types for code, canvases, mind maps and diagrams.</li>
      <li>Attributes (labels and relations) for organising, querying and scripting notes.</li>
      <li>Scriptable and extensible with a built-in JavaScript API and a note-map / relation-map to visualise connections.</li>
      <li>Strong note encryption to protect sensitive notes on a per-note basis.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Permissions: this package keeps a tight sandbox by default — network (for optional server sync), display, GPU and notifications. Importing and exporting notes goes through the desktop portal, so no broad filesystem access is granted; the note database lives inside the sandbox under ~/.var/app/com.triliumnext.notes. To share a note database with a host location, grant filesystem access and set TRILIUM_DATA_DIR via <code>flatpak override</code>.</p>
  </description>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <categories>
    <category>Office</category>
    <category>Utility</category>
  </categories>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>notes</keyword>
    <keyword>knowledgebase</keyword>
    <keyword>outliner</keyword>
    <keyword>markdown</keyword>
    <keyword>wiki</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <recommends>
    <display_length compare="ge">800</display_length>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
  </recommends>
  <provides>
    <binary>trilium</binary>
  </provides>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.triliumnext.notes.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/TriliumNext/Trilium/main/apps/website/original-images/screenshot_desktop_linux_light.png</image>
      <caption>Hierarchical note tree and rich text editor (light theme)</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/TriliumNext/Trilium/main/apps/website/original-images/screenshot_desktop_linux_dark.png</image>
      <caption>Hierarchical note tree and rich text editor (dark theme)</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.104.0" date="2026-07-18" />
    <release version="0.103.0" date="2026-05-13">
      <url>https://github.com/TriliumNext/Trilium/releases/tag/v0.103.0</url>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
